Okay, we'll do an exercise. Someone asks Rob, "Hey Rob! Were you at the theater the other night?" Rob can reply in many ways.
Rob can say, "No!
I wasn't in the theater the other night," or Rob can say, "No.
I don't believe I was.
I was at home watching TV."
So this way, we have a short response and a long response.
Also Rob could say, "No!
That's preposterous!
I would never go to the theater.
I don't like the theater.
I find it not to be my cup of tea," and then he uses cliches to influence and to add a little embellishment to his line and he says big words like "preposterous."
This can give us clues into a character.
This character might be shy.
This character might just be--likes to explain things and he might be more of an extrovert.
A character who would say a word like "preposterous" might just be--might be someone who's kind of pompous.
These give us clues, clues into who the characters are.
How they talk gives us clues.